fortrade.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy

                                  Privacy Policy
Fort Securities Australia Pty. Ltd.
ABN 33 614 683 831
Australian Financial Services Licence No. 493520
Date: 15 February 2019

                                                          Contents
SECTION A – INTRODUCTION ............................................................................................................................................4
  1. INTRODUCTION..................................................................................................................... 4
  2. WHEN DOES THIS POLICY APPLY? ........................................................................................... 4
  3. GLOSSARY ............................................................................................................................. 4
SECTION B – CONSIDERATION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION PRIVACY ............................................................................5
  4. PRIVACY STATEMENT ............................................................................................................ 5
SECTION C – COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION (SOLICITED PERSONAL INFORMATION) ..................................6
  5. PERSONAL INFORMATION (OTHER THAN SENSITIVE INFORMATION) .......................................6
  7. MEANS OF COLLECTION ........................................................................................................ 6
  8. INFORMATION COLLECTED BY FORT SECURITIES AUSTRALIA .................................................. 6
  9. PURPOSE OF COLLECTION ..................................................................................................... 6
SECTION D – COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION (UNSOLICITED PERSONAL INFORMATION) .............................7
  10. DEALING WITH UNSOLICITED PERSONAL INFORMATION ....................................................... 7
SECTION E – NOTIFICATION OF THE COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION.............................................................7
  11. NOTIFICATION OF COLLECTION........................................................................................... 7
SECTION F – USE OR DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION .....................................................................................8
  12. USE OR DISCLOSURE ............................................................................................................ 8
  13. WHO DOES FORT SECURITIES AUSTRALIA DISLCOSE PERSONAL INFORMATION .....................8
SECTION G – DIRECT MARKETING .....................................................................................................................................9
  14. DIRECT MARKETING ............................................................................................................ 9
  16. EXCEPTION – SENSITIVE INFORMATION .............................................................................. 10
  17. REQUESTS TO STOP DIRECT MARKETING............................................................................ 10
SECTION H – CROSS BORDER DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION .....................................................................10
  18. DISCLOSING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO CROSS BORDER RECIPIENTS ..............................10
SECTION I – ADOPTION, USE OR DISCLOSURE OF GOVERNMENT IDENTIFIERS ..............................................................11
  19. ADOPTION OF GOVERNMENT RELATED IDENTIFIERS........................................................... 11
  20. USE OR DISCLOSURE OF GOVERNMENT RELATED IDENTIFIERS ............................................11
SECTION J – INTEGRITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION....................................................................................................11
  21. QUALITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION .............................................................................. 11
  22. SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION ............................................................................. 11
SECTION K – ACCESS TO, AND CORRECTION OF, PESRONAL INFORMATION ..................................................................12
  24. ACCESS ............................................................................................................................. 12
  25. EXCEPTIONS ...................................................................................................................... 12
  26. REFUSAL TO GIVE ACCESS ................................................................................................. 13
SECTION L – CORRECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION ...............................................................................................13
  27. CORRECTION OF INFORMATION ........................................................................................ 13
  28. REFUSAL TO CORRECT INFORMATION................................................................................ 13
                                          F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                                    c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                             Page 2 of 14

  29. REQUEST FROM A CLIENT TO ASSOCIATE A STATEMENT WITH THEIR INFORMATION ..........13
  30. DEALING WITH REQUESTS .................................................................................................. 14
SECTION M – MISCELLANEOUS .......................................................................................................................................14
  31. POLICY BREACHES ............................................................................................................. 14
  32. RETENTION OF FORMS....................................................................................................... 14
                                       F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                                 c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                              Page 3 of 14

                                           SECTION A – INTRODUCTION
1. INTRODUCTION
    1.1 As part of Fort Securities Australia Pty Ltd’s (“Fort Securities Australia”) process to
    ensure that it continues to maintain the highest levels of professional integrity and ethical
    conduct, Fort Securities Australia has adopted this Privacy Policy (“Policy”) to manage
    personal information in an open and transparent manner.
    1.2 The provisions of this Policy will assist Fort Securities Australia in complying with the
    requirements of the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and the Australian Privacy Principles in
    protecting the personal information Fort Securities Australia holds about its clients.
2. WHEN DOES THIS POLICY APPLY?
    2.1 This Policy applies to all representatives and employees of Fort Securities Australia at all
    times and the requirements remain in force on an ongoing basis.
3. GLOSSARY
           TERM                         DEFINITION
                                        means an agency or organisation as defined in section 6 of the
           APP entity
                                        Privacy Act 1988.
                                        (a) an Act of the Commonwealth or of a State or Territory; or
                                        (b) regulations, or any other instrument, made under such an
           Australian law means         Act; or
                                        (c) a Norfolk Island enactment; or
                                        (d) a rule of common law or equity.
                                        Fort Securities Australia collects personal information only if Fort
           Collects                     Securities Australia collects the personal information for inclusion
                                        in a record or generally available publication.
                                        means an order, direction or other instrument made by:
                                        (a) a court; or
                                        (b) a tribunal; or
                                        (c) a judge (including a judge acting in a personal capacity) or a
                                        person acting as a judge; or
           Court/tribunal order
                                        (d) a magistrate (including a magistrate acting in a personal
                                        capacity) or a person acting as a magistrate; or
                                        (e) a member or an officer of a tribunal;
                                        and includes an order, direction or other instrument that is of an
                                        interim or interlocutory nature.
                                        personal information is de-identified if the information is no
           De-identified                longer about an identifiable individual or an individual who is
                                        reasonably identifiable.
                                        Fort Securities Australia holds personal information if it has
           Holds                        possession or control of a record that contains the personal
                                        information.
                                        means a number, letter or symbol, or a combination of any or all
                                        of those things, that is used to identify the individual or to verify
                                        the identity of the
           Identifier of an             individual, but does not include:
           individual                   (a) the individual’s name; or
                                        (b) the individual’s ABN (within the meaning of the A New Tax
                                        System (Australian Business Number) Act 1999); or
                                        (c) anything else prescribed by the regulations.
           Permitted general
                                        As defined in s16A of the Privacy Act 1988
           situation
           Permitted health
                                        As defined in s16B of the Privacy Act 1988
           situation
                                      F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                                c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                            Page 4 of 14

                                           means information or an opinion about an identified individual, or
                                           an individual who is reasonably identifiable:
             Personal information          (a) whether the information or opinion is true or not; and
                                           (b) whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material
                                           form or not.
                                           means
                                           (a) information or an opinion about an individual’s:
                                           (i) racial or ethnic origin; or
                                           (ii) political opinions; or
                                           (iii) membership of a political association; or
                                           (iv) religious beliefs or affiliations; or
                                           (v) philosophical beliefs; or
                                           (vi) membership of a professional or trade association; or
                                           (vii) membership of a trade union; or
             Sensitive information
                                           (viii) sexual orientation or practices; or
                                           (ix) criminal record;
                                           that is also personal information; or
                                           (b) health information about an individual; or
                                           (c) genetic information about an individual that is not otherwise
                                           health information.
                                           (d) biometric information that is to be used for the purpose of
                                           automated biometric verification or biometric identification; or
                                           (e) biometric templates.
                     SECTION B – CONSIDERATION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION PRIVACY
4. PRIVACY STATEMENT
    4.1 Fort Securities Australia’s Compliance Officer must ensure that at all times the provisions of
    this policy are implemented in the day to day running of Fort Securities Australia.
    4.2 The Compliance Officer must ensure that at all times this Policy:
        (a) is current and reflects the latest applicable Australian laws; and
        (b) contains the following information:
             (i) the kinds of personal information that Fort Securities Australia collects and
             holds;
             (ii) how Fort Securities Australia collects and holds personal information;
             (iii) the purposes for which Fort Securities Australia collects, holds, uses and
             discloses personal information;
             (iv) how an individual may complain about a breach of the Australian Privacy
             Principles, or other relevant legislation that binds Fort Securities Australia,
             and how Fort Securities Australia will deal with such a complaint;
             (v) whether Fort Securities Australia is likely to disclose personal information to
             overseas recipients;
             (vi) if Fort Securities Australia is likely to disclose personal information to
             overseas recipients, the countries in which such recipients are likely to be
             located if it is practicable to specify those countries in this policy.
    4.3 Fort Securities Australia must ensure that the Fort Securities Australia’s Privacy Statement
    is available free of charge and in such form as appropriate. Fort Securities Australia will
    make the Privacy Statement available on its website.
    4.4 If the Privacy Statement is requested in a particular form, Fort Securities Australia will take
    such steps as are reasonable to provide the Privacy Statement in the form requested.
                                         F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                                   c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                            Page 5 of 14

            SECTION C – COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION (SOLICITED PERSONAL
                                                              INFORMATION)
5. PERSONAL INFORMATION (OTHER THAN SENSITIVE INFORMATION)
    5.1 This Section C applies to the collection of personal information that is solicited by Fort
    Securities Australia.
    5.2 Fort Securities Australia must not collect personal information (other than sensitive
    information) unless the information is reasonably necessary for one or more of Fort
    Securities Australia’s functions or activities.
    5.3 Fort Securities Australia’s functions or activities include:
       (a) provide general financial product advice;
       (b) provide dealing services for certain financial products; and
       (c) make a market for certain financial products.
    6. SENSITIVE INFORMATION
    6.1 Fort Securities Australia must not collect sensitive information about an individual unless:
       (a) the individual consents to the collection of the information and the information is
       reasonably necessary for one or more of Fort Securities Australia’s functions or
       activities (as described in section 5.3); or
       (b) the collection of the information is required or authorised by or under an Australian
       law or a Court/Tribunal order; or
       (c) a permitted general situation exists in relation to the collection of the information by
       Fort Securities Australia; or
       (d) a permitted health situation exists in relation to the collection of the information by
       Fort Securities Australia.
7. MEANS OF COLLECTION
    7.1 Fort Securities Australia must only collect personal information by lawful and fair means.
    7.2 Fort Securities Australia must only collect personal information about an individual from the
    individual (rather than someone else), unless it is unreasonable or impracticable to do so or
    the individual has instructed Fort Securities Australia to liaise with someone else.
    7.3 Fort Securities Australia will collect personal information from an individual when:
       (a) Fort Securities Australia’s Application Form is completed;
       (b) a Client provides the information to Fort Securities Australia’s representatives over
       the telephone or via email;
       (c) a Client provides the information to Fort Securities Australia on the website;
       (d) a client registers for demo/practice account;
       (e) marketing/promotional material is provided to a client.
8. INFORMATION COLLECTED BY FORT SECURITIES AUSTRALIA
    8.1 The information Fort Securities Australia collects may include the following:
       (a) name;
       (b) date of birth;
       (c) postal or email address; or
       (d) phone numbers;
       (e) other information Fort Securities Australia considers necessary to their functions and
       activities.
9. PURPOSE OF COLLECTION
    9.1 If an individual is acquiring or has acquired a product or service from Fort Securities
    Australia, the individual’s personal information will be collected and held for the purposes of:
                                      F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                                c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                            Page 6 of 14

   (a) checking whether an individual is eligible for Fort Securities Australia’s product or
   service;
   (b) providing the individual with Fort Securities Australia’s product or service;
   (c) managing and administering Fort Securities Australia’s product or service;
   (d) protecting against fraud, crime or other activity which may cause harm in relation to
   Fort Securities Australia’s products or services;
   (e) complying with legislative and regulatory requirements in any jurisdiction;
   (f) to assist Fort Securities Australia in the running of its business.
   9.2 Fort Securities Australia may also collect personal information for the purposes of letting an
   individual know about products or services that might better serve their needs or other
   opportunities in which they may be interested. Please refer to Section G for further
   information.
         SECTION D – COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION (UNSOLICITED PERSONAL
                                                               INFORMATION)
10. DEALING WITH UNSOLICITED PERSONAL INFORMATION
   10.1 If Fort Securities Australia:
       (a) receives personal information about an individual; and
       (b) the information is not solicited by Fort Securities Australia
   Fort Securities Australia must, within a reasonable period after receiving the information,
   determine whether or not it was permitted to collect the information under Section C above.
   10.2 Fort Securities Australia may use or disclose the personal information for the purposes of
   making the determination under paragraph 10.1.
   10.3 If Fort Securities Australia:
       (a) determines that it could not have collected the personal information; and
       (b) the information is not contained in a Commonwealth record,
       Fort Securities Australia must as soon as practicable, destroy the information or ensure that
       the information is de-identified, only if it is lawful and reasonable to do so.
            SECTION E – NOTIFICATION OF THE COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
11. NOTIFICATION OF COLLECTION
   11.1 This section 11 applies to:
       (a) solicited information; and
       (b) unsolicited information to which section 10 does not apply.
   11.2 Fort Securities Australia must notify the individual of the following matters in the Privacy
   Statement:
       (a) Fort Securities Australia’s identity and contact details;
       (b) if Fort Securities Australia collects the personal information from a third party or the
       individual is not aware that Fort Securities Australia has collected the personal
       information, the fact that Fort Securities Australia so collects, or has collected the
       information and the circumstances of that collection;
       (c) if the collection of the personal information is required or authorised by or under an
       Australian law or a Court/Tribunal order, the fact that the collection is so required or
       authorised (including the details of the law or court);
                                       F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                                 c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                            Page 7 of 14

      (d) the purposes for which Fort Securities Australia collects the personal information;
      (e) the main consequences (if any) for the individual if the information is not collected by
      Fort Securities Australia;
      (f) any other entities to which Fort Securities Australia usually discloses personal
      information of the kind collected by Fort Securities Australia;
      (g) that Fort Securities Australia’s Privacy Statement and this Privacy Policy contains
      information about how the individual may access the personal information about the
      individual that is held by Fort Securities Australia and seek correction of such
      information;
      (h) that Fort Securities Australia’s Privacy Statement contains information about how the
      individual may complain about a breach of the Australian Privacy Principles and how
      Fort Securities Australia will deal with such a complaint;
      (i) whether Fort Securities Australia will disclose the personal information to overseas
      recipients; and
      (j) if Fort Securities Australia discloses the personal information to overseas recipients
      – the countries in which such recipients will be located if it is practicable to specify
      those countries in the notification or to otherwise make the individual aware of them.
                       SECTION F – USE OR DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
12. USE OR DISCLOSURE
   12.1 Where Fort Securities Australia holds personal information about an individual that was
   collected for a particular purpose (“the primary purpose”), Fort Securities Australia must not
   use or disclose the information for another purpose (“the secondary purpose”) unless:
      (a) the individual has consented to the use or disclosure of the information; or
      (b) the individual would reasonably expect Fort Securities Australia to use or disclose
      the information for the secondary purpose and the secondary purpose is:
            (i) directly related to the primary purpose (if the information is sensitive
            information); or
            (ii) related to the primary purpose (if the information is not sensitive information);
      (c) the use or disclosure of the information is required or authorised by or under an
      Australian law or a Court/Tribunal order; or
      (d) a permitted general situation exists in relation to the use or disclosure of the
      information by Fort Securities Australia; or
      (e) Fort Securities Australia reasonably believes that the use or disclosure of the
      information is reasonably necessary for one or more enforcement related activities
      conducted by, or on behalf of, an enforcement body.
   12.2 Where Fort Securities Australia uses or discloses personal information in accordance with
   section 12.1(e), Fort Securities Australia will keep a copy of this disclosure (e.g.: the email
   or letter used to do so).
   12.3 This section 12 does not apply to:
      (a) personal information for the purposes of direct marketing; or
      (b) government related identifiers.
   12.4 If Fort Securities Australia collects personal information from a related body corporate, this
   section 12 applies as if Fort Securities Australia’s primary purpose for the collection was the
   primary purpose for which the related body corporate collected the information.
13. WHO DOES FORT SECURITIES AUSTRALIA DISLCOSE PERSONAL INFORMATION
                                        F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                                  c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                            Page 8 of 14

   TO?
   13.1 Fort Securities Australia may disclose personal information collected from clients and
   prospective clients to the following:
      (a) organisations involved in providing, managing or administering Fort Securities
      Australia’s product or service such as third party suppliers, e.g. printers, posting
      services, and our advisers;
      (b) organisations involved in maintaining, reviewing and developing Fort Securities
      Australia’s business systems, procedures and infrastructure, including testing or
      upgrading Fort Securities Australia’s computer systems;
      (c) organisations involved in a corporate re-organisation;
      (d) organisations involved in the payments system, including financial institutions,
      merchants and payment organisations;
      (e) organisations involved in product planning and development;
      (f) other organisations, who jointly with Fort Securities Australia’s, provide its products
      or services;
      (g) authorised representatives who provide Fort Securities Australia’s products or
      services on its behalf;
      (h) the individual’s representatives, including your legal advisers;
      (i) debt collectors;
      (j) Fort Securities Australia’s financial advisers, legal advisers or auditors;
      (k) fraud bureaus or other organisations to identify, investigate or prevent fraud or other
      misconduct;
      (l) external dispute resolution schemes; or
      (m) regulatory bodies, government agencies and law enforcement bodies in any
      jurisdiction.
                                        SECTION G – DIRECT MARKETING
14. DIRECT MARKETING
   14.1 Fort Securities Australia must not use or disclose the personal information it holds about an
   individual for the purpose of direct marketing.
   15. EXCEPTION – PERSONAL INFORMATION OTHER THAN SENSITIVE INFORMATION
   15.1 Fort Securities Australia may use or disclose personal information (other than sensitive
   information) about an individual for the purposes of direct marketing if:
      (a) Fort Securities Australia collected the information from the individual; and the
      individual would reasonably expect Fort Securities Australia to use or disclose the
      information for that purpose; or
      (b) Fort Securities Australia has collected the information from a third party; and either:
           (i) Fort Securities Australia has obtained the individual’s consent to the use or
           disclose the information for the purpose of direct marketing; or
           (ii) it is impracticable for Fort Securities Australia to obtain the individual’s
      consent; and
      (c) in each direct marketing communication with the individual Fort Securities Australia:
           (i) includes a prominent statement that the individual may make such a request; or
           (ii) directs the individual’s attention to the fact that the individual may make such
      a request; and
      (d) the individual has not made such a request.
                                        F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                                  c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                            Page 9 of 14

16. EXCEPTION – SENSITIVE INFORMATION
   16.1 Fort Securities Australia may use or disclose sensitive information about an individual for
   the purpose of direct marketing if the individual has consented to the use or disclosure of
   the information for that purpose.
17. REQUESTS TO STOP DIRECT MARKETING
   17.1 Where Fort Securities Australia uses or discloses personal information about an individual
   for the purposes of direct marketing by Fort Securities Australia or facilitating direct
   marketing by another organisation, the individual may request:
      (a) that Fort Securities Australia no longer provide them with direct marketing
      communications;
      (b) that Fort Securities Australia does not use or disclose the individual’s personal
      information for the purpose of facilitating direct marketing by another organisation;
      (c) that Fort Securities Australia provides the source of the personal information.
   17.2 Where Fort Securities Australia receives a request from an individual under section 17.1,
   Fort Securities Australia will:
      (a) give effect to the request under section 17.1(a) or 17.1(b) within a reasonable period
      after the request is made and free of charge; and
      (b) notify the individual of the source of the information, if the individual requests it,
      unless it is impracticable or unreasonable to do so.
   17.3 This Section G does not apply to the extent that the following laws apply:
      (a) the Do Not Call Register Act 2006;
      (b) the Spam Act 2003; or
      (c) any other Act of the Commonwealth of Australia.
                 SECTION H – CROSS BORDER DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
18. DISCLOSING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO CROSS BORDER RECIPIENTS
   18.1 Where Fort Securities Australia discloses personal information about an individual to a
   recipient who is not in Australia and who is not Fort Securities Australia or the individual,
   Fort Securities Australia must ensure that the overseas recipient does not breach the
   Australian Privacy Principles (with the exception of APP1).
   18.2 The countries we may disclose an individual’s personal information to include:
      (a) United Kingdom.
   18.3 Section 18.1 does not apply where:
      (a) Fort Securities Australia reasonably believes that:
           (i) information is subject to a law or binding scheme that has the effect of
           protecting the information in a way that is at least substantially similar to the
           way in which the Australian Privacy Principles protect the information; and
           (ii) there are mechanisms that the individual can access to take action to enforce
      that protection of the law or binding scheme; or
      (b) both of the following apply:
           (i) Fort Securities Australia has informed the individual that if they consent to the
           disclosure of information Fort Securities Australia will not take reasonable
           steps to ensure the overseas recipient does not breach the Australian Privacy
           Principles; and
           (ii) after being so informed, the individual consents to disclosure;
      (c) the disclosure of the information is required or authorised by or under an Australian
                                      F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                                c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                            Page 10 of 14

       law or a Court/Tribunal order; or
       (d) a permitted general situation (other than the situation referred to in item 4 or 5 of the
       table in subsection 16A(1) Privacy Act) exists in relation to the disclosure of the
       information by Fort Securities Australia.
             SECTION I – ADOPTION, USE OR DISCLOSURE OF GOVERNMENT IDENTIFIERS
19. ADOPTION OF GOVERNMENT RELATED IDENTIFIERS
   19.1 Fort Securities Australia must not adopt a government related identifier of an individual as
   its own identifier unless:
       (a) Fort Securities Australia is required or authorised by or under an Australian law or a
       Court/Tribunal order to do so; or
       (b) the identifier, Fort Securities Australia and the circumstances of the adoption are
       prescribed by regulations.
   Commented [MG3]: Please advise.
20. USE OR DISCLOSURE OF GOVERNMENT RELATED IDENTIFIERS
   20.1 Before using or disclosing a government related identifier of an individual, Fort Securities
   Australia must ensure that such use or disclosure is:
       (a) reasonably necessary for Fort Securities Australia to verify the identity of the
       individual for the purposes of the organisation’s activities or functions; or
       (b) reasonably necessary for the organisation to fulfil its obligations to an agency or a
       State or Territory authority; or
       (c) required or authorised by or under an Australian law or a Court/Tribunal order; or
       (d) within a permitted general situation (other than the situation referred to in item 4 or 5
       of the table in subsection 16A(1) Privacy Act; or
       (e) reasonably necessary for one or more enforcement related activities conducted by,
       or on behalf of, an enforcement body; or
       (f) the identifier, Fort Securities Australia and the circumstances of the adoption are
       prescribed by regulations.
                            SECTION J – INTEGRITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
21. QUALITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
   21.1 Fort Securities Australia will ensure that the personal information it collects and the personal
   information it uses or discloses is, having regard to the purpose of the use or disclosure,
   accurate, up to date, complete and relevant.
22. SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
   22.1 Fort Securities Australia will ensure that it protects any personal information it holds from
   misuse, interference, loss, unauthorised access, modification and disclosure.
   22.2 Fort Securities Australia will take reasonable steps to destroy or de-identify any personal
   information it holds where:
       (a) Fort Securities Australia no longer needs the personal information for any purpose
       for which the information may be used or disclosed by Fort Securities Australia;
       (b) the information is not contained in a Commonwealth record;
       (c) Fort Securities Australia is not required to retain that information under an Australian
       law, or a Court/Tribunal order.
                                       F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                                 c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                            Page 11 of 14

   23. STORAGE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
   23.1 Fort Securities Australia stores personal information in different ways, including:
      (a) hard copy on site at Fort Securities Australia’s head office; and
      (b) electronically secure data centres which are located in Australia and owned by either
   Fort Securities Australia or external service providers.
   23.2 In order to ensure Fort Securities Australia protects any personal information it holds from
   misuse, interference, loss, unauthorised access, modification and disclosure, Fort Securities
   Australia implements the following procedure/system:
      (a) access to information systems is controlled through identity and access
      management;
      (b) employees are bound by internal information securities policies and are required to
      keep information secure; and
      (c) all employees are required to complete training about information security; and
      (d) Fort Securities Australia regularly monitors and reviews its compliance with internal
      policies and industry best practice.
              SECTION K – ACCESS TO, AND CORRECTION OF, PESRONAL INFORMATION
24. ACCESS
   24.1 Fort Securities Australia must give an individual access to the personal information it holds
   about the individual if so requested by the individual.
   24.2 Fort Securities Australia must respond to any request for access to personal information
   within a reasonable period after the request is made.
   24.3 Fort Securities Australia must give access to the information in the manner requested by the
   individual, if it is reasonable and practicable to do so and must take such steps as are
   reasonable in the circumstances to give access in a way that meets the needs of Fort
   Securities Australia and the individual.
   24.4 Fort Securities Australia must not charge an individual for making a request and must not
   impose excessive charges for the individual to access their personal information.
25. EXCEPTIONS
   25.1 Fort Securities Australia is not required to give an individual access to their personal
   information if:
      (a) Fort Securities Australia reasonably believes that giving access would pose a
      serious threat to the life, health or safety of any individual, or to public health or
      public safety; or
      (b) giving access would have an unreasonable impact on the privacy of other
      individuals; or
      (c) the request for access if frivolous or vexatious; or
      (d) the information relates to existing or anticipated legal proceedings between Fort
      Securities Australia and the individual, and would not be accessible by the process
      of discovery in those proceedings; or
      (e) giving access would reveal intentions of Fort Securities Australia in relation to
      negotiations with the individual in such a way as to prejudice those negotiations; or
      (f) giving access would be unlawful; or
      (g) denying access is required or authorised by or under an Australian law or a
      Court/Tribunal order; or
      (h) Fort Securities Australia has reason that unlawful activity, or misconduct of a serious
                                     F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                               c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                            Page 12 of 14

      nature, that relates to our functions or activities has been, or may be engaged in and
      giving access would be likely to prejudice the taking of appropriate action in relation
      to the matter; or
      (i) giving access would be likely to prejudice one or more enforcement related activities
      conducted by, or on behalf of, an enforcement body; or
      (j) giving access would reveal evaluative information generated within Fort Securities
      Australia in connection with a commercially sensitive decision-making process.
26. REFUSAL TO GIVE ACCESS
   26.1 If Fort Securities Australia refuses to give access in accordance with section 24 or to give
   access in the manner requested by the individual, Fort Securities Australia will give the
   individual a written notice that sets out:
      (a) the reasons for the refusal except to the extent that, having regard to the grounds for
      the refusal, it would be unreasonable to do so; and
      (b) the mechanisms available to complain about the refusal; and
      (c) any other matter prescribed by the regulations.
   26.2 Where Fort Securities Australia refuses to give access under section 25.1(j) Fort Securities
   Australia may include an explanation of the commercially sensitive decision in its written
   notice of the reasons for denial.
                        SECTION L – CORRECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
27. CORRECTION OF INFORMATION
   27.1 Fort Securities Australia must take reasonable steps to correct all personal information,
   having regard to the purpose for which the information is held where:
      (a) Fort Securities Australia is satisfied the information is inaccurate, out of date,
      incomplete, irrelevant or misleading; or
      (b) the individual requests Fort Securities Australia corrects the information.
   27.2 Where Fort Securities Australia corrects personal information about an individual that Fort
   Securities Australia previously disclosed to another APP entity and the individual requests
   Fort Securities Australia to notify the other APP entity of the correction, Fort Securities
   Australia must take reasonable steps to give that notification, unless it is impracticable or
   unlawful to do so.
28. REFUSAL TO CORRECT INFORMATION
   28.1 If Fort Securities Australia refuses to correct personal information as requested by the
   individual, Fort Securities Australia will give the individual a written notice that sets out:
      (a) the reasons for the refusal except to the extent that it would be unreasonable to do
      so; and
      (b) the mechanisms available to complain about the refusal; and
      (c) any other matter prescribed by the regulations.
29. REQUEST FROM A CLIENT TO ASSOCIATE A STATEMENT WITH THEIR INFORMATION
   29.1 If:
      (a) Fort Securities Australia refuses to correct personal information as requested by the
      individual; and
      (b) the individual requests that Fort Securities Australia associate a statement noting
      that the information is inaccurate, out of date, incomplete, irrelevant or misleading,
      with the individual’s information,
      Fort Securities Australia must take such steps as are reasonable in the circumstances to
                                     F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                               c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                            Page 13 of 14

      associate the statement (as described in section 29.1(b)) with the individual’s personal
      information. The statement should be associated with the information in such a way that will
      make the statement apparent to users of the information.
30. DEALING WITH REQUESTS
   30.1 Fort Securities Australia must:
      (a) respond to requests under this Section L within a reasonable period after the request
      is made; and
      (b) must not charge the individual for the making of the request, for correcting the
      personal information or for associating the statement with the personal information.
                                        SECTION M – MISCELLANEOUS
31. POLICY BREACHES
   31.1 Breaches of this Policy may lead to disciplinary action being taken against the relevant
   party, including dismissal in serious cases and may also result in prosecution under the law
   where that act is illegal. This may include re-assessment of bonus qualification, termination
   of employment and/or fines (in accordance with the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth)).
   31.2 Staff are trained internally on compliance and their regulatory obligation to Fort Securities
   Australia. They are encouraged to respond appropriately to and report all breaches of the
   law and other incidents of non-compliance, including Fort Securities Australia’s policies, and
   seek guidance if they are unsure.
   31.3 Staff must report breaches of this Policy directly to the Compliance Officer.
32. RETENTION OF FORMS
   32.1 The Compliance Officer will retain the completed forms for seven (7) years in accordance
   with Fort Securities Australia’s Document Retention Policy. The completed forms are
   retained for future reference and review.
   32.2 As part of their training, all staff are made aware of the need to practice thorough and up to
   date record keeping, not only as a way of meeting Fort Securities Australia’s compliance
   obligations, but as a way of minimising risk.
   Issued by Fort Securities Australia Pty Ltd
   March 2019
                                     F o r t S e c u r i t i e s A u s t r a l i a P t y L t d (A C N 6 1 4 6 8 3 8 3 1)
                                               c / o Level 5, 20 Bond Street, Sydney NSW 2000                            Page 14 of 14
